# Miguel Vicente Ortega Santiago

# Web Developer

Penrith, NSW Australia | M: 0499 398 311 | E: santiagomiguelvicente@gmail.com | L: www.linkedin.com/in/miguel-vicente-ortega-santiago

Developer Portfolio: <a href="https://miguelvicentesantiago-migscay.vercel.app/">https://miguelvicentesantiago-migscay.vercel.app/</a>

#### **TECH SKILLS**

- Javascript
- HTML/CSS
- Bootstrap
- NPM
- React
- MS Office
- GIT/Github
- C#
- PHP
- Laravel
- Vue
- MySQL
- MongoDb
- LANSA
- RPG/400
- COBOL

#### TRANSFERRABLE SKILLS

- Time Management
- Adaptability
- Teamwork
- Analytical skills
- · Problem-solving skills
- Innovative
- Troubleshooting skills
- Proactive

#### PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

#### MongoDB University

- M001: MongoDB Basics May 2018
- M101JS: MongoDB for NodeJS Developers September 2018

### LANSA

Lansa Integrator Course March 2012

#### Computer Power

 Graduate Certificate in Object Oriented Programming August 2005

#### LinkedIn

- PHP with MySQL Essential Training: 1 The Basics November 2018
- PHP with MySQL Essential Training: 2 Build a CMS November 2018
- PHP Essential Training November 2018
- Learning PHP October 2018

## **EDUCATION**

# University of the East - Caloocan city, PH

 Bachelor of Business Administration, Majoring in Accounting, 1990

# REFERENCES

- Robin Klaus Instructor at Generation Australia JWD program
- Anthony Belz Senior Analyst/Programmer at PICA
- Natalie Wedd Systems Development Manager at PICA

#### OTHER LANGUAGES

PILIPINO/TAGALOG

### **ABOUT ME**

Experienced Analyst/Programmer with over a decade of experience. I have recently completed a bootcamp in Web Development. With my knowledge and experience in coding, I can help create effective systems to assist businesses effectively connect with their customers. I am excited to apply my strengths in diagnosing and developing innovative solutions. I am good with React, my Developer Portfolio is developed with React/Bootstrap.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Web Development Volunteer Contributor

ISGOOD.AI

Feb 2021 - Present

- Study Blitz.js a Full Stack Web Development Framework
- . Contribute to redevelopment of the Web App

#### Junior Web Development Bootcamp Graduate

Generation Australia in Partnership with Academy Xi

Nov 2020 - Mar 2021

- · Completed the full-time intensive web development program by Generation Australia and facilitated by AcademyXi
- Skills and Languages covered: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, NPM as well as behavioural/people skills to support
  job readiness
- Completed a final project (development of Task-Planner Web App) using the skills learned across the course

#### Analyst/Programmer

PRUDENTIAL INVESTMENT COMPANY OF AUSTRALIA

Feb 2008 - Dec 2018

- Maintained and added modules to the Portfolio Management System which is running on the AS/400 and developed using LANSA
- In example, I added the Online Invoice Approval module that sped up the processing of thousands of invoices per day
- Done maintenance changes on the company's intranet site which is developed in Java EE and run under the IBM Portal platform
- Created new and revised existing Crystal Report definitions and the stored procedure written in LANSA to get data from PMS

### Java Programmer Trainee

IC CONSULTING

Jun 2005 - Jan 2008

- Studied Java programming and got certified as Sun Cerified Java Programmer
- Compose Change request proposals based on requirements of the client
- Develop/revise Java Server Pagess, Java servlets and Enterprise Java Beans for the change requests from clients

# Analyst/Programmer

Software Laboratories Incorporated

Oct 2000 - Dec 2002

Assigned at GOODYEAR PHILIPPINES

 Develop/revise RPG/400 programs as per specifications approved by the users for additional reports on the AS/400 systems

# Analyst/Programmer

MASTECH ASIA PACIFIC, Sydney Australia

Sep 1998 - Aug 2000

Assigned at ASTRE Automotive Group

- Develop/revise RPG/400 or RPG IV programs as per specifications prepared by the JBA Business Analyst
- Investigated issues and explained whether it was a system setup issue, data conversion or if something was wrong
  with the program

#### Assigned at SSA ASIA PACIFIC

- Make high level estimates on what are the required activities and corresponding man-hours to satisfy user
- · Make technical design according to user requirements
- · Develop/revise AS/SET definition according to technical design

#### Analyst/Programmer

EASTERN TELECOMS PHILS. INC.

- One of the Developers that developed and implemented the Customer Service Systsem using RPG and CL/400
- Maintained and provided user support for the Billing system

# EDP Manager

AMOY FASHION GLOVES, XIAMEN CHINA May 1994 - Mar 1997

- Studied the manufacturing system developed in New York and implemented the system in the Factory
- Provide user training for the system

## Analyst/Programmer

Software Laboratories Incorporated Oct 2000 - Dec 2002 Assigned at SMITHKLINE BEECHAM PHILIPPINES

Design and implement additional reports on the JD Edwards accounting package

#### Programmer

RUSTAN'S COMMERCIAL CORPORATION Feb 1990 - Jul 1993

- COBOL programming on the different systems running on the NCR 9050 mainframe.
- Saved the Comapny Time and Money by Developing and implementing the MTS Preparation system on the PC using FoxBASE+ and developing the interface programs on the AS/400